const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",a=200,t=120,o=[{id:129,question:"The  payment  made  by  underwriter  as  a  form  of  	kindness  without  admission  of  liability  so  as  to maintain goodwill is known as ------------",option:{a:"Kindness payment",b:"Ex-gratia payment",c:"Favour payment",d:"Claim"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:284,question:"Return premium is the same thing as",option:{a:"premium payment",b:"premium refund",c:"premium tax",d:"premium bonus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:346,question:"The saving element in a permanent life assurance policy which represent the policyholder’s interest in the policy is",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"cash value",c:"sum assured",d:"residual value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:180,question:"A person who makes an insurance claim is called",option:{a:"Actuary",b:"Adjustor",c:"Claimant",d:"Client"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:251,question:"Insurance premium depends on the",option:{a:"amount of profit to be made by the insurer",b:"various insurance companies in a place",c:"extent of the possible loss and the frequency of risk",d:"supply and demand"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:288,question:"Marine  losses are divided into",option:{a:"actual total and total loss",b:"total loss and partial loss",c:"partial loss and actual loss",d:"average loss and partial loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:24,question:"Ade insured his property for N= 350,000.00. The property is subject to average condition. He suffered a loss amounting to N= 30,000.00 with the value of the property at the time of loss to be N= 370,000.00. How much will the insurer pay?",option:{a:"N= 14,583.33",b:"N= 28,378.38",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 31,714.29"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:78,question:"Factors which may influence the occurrence of a loss is",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Loss",c:"Peril",d:"Hazard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:39,question:"The payment made when the insured is  not  entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:181,question:"To break or act contrary to a law or promise means",option:{a:"Breach",b:"Shake",c:"Confirm",d:"Disagreement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:229,question:"One of the following is a condition for contribution",option:{a:"bilateral interest",b:"multilatual interest",c:"two subject matter",d:"common subject matter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:281,question:"The process of examining, accepting or rejecting risks and classifying the ones accepted is",option:{a:"underwriting",b:"policy",c:"procedures",d:"warranty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:267,question:"One of this is the consideration paid for insurance contract",option:{a:"fee",b:"cheque",c:"commission",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:44,question:"Insurers A and B cover a risk at the ratio of 2:5 for the sum insured of N= 1,800. How much would insurer  A get from the risk?",option:{a:"N= 1,285.00",b:"N= 771.00",c:"N= 514.00",d:"N= 180.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:56,question:"A fundamental condition which must be filled  by the  insured for compensation is",option:{a:"warranty",b:"obligation",c:"interest",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:134,question:"A house worth N=60,000 insured against fire for N=40,000.  Fire destroyed and cause damage worth N=30,000. On the house under which insurance principle will the owner be entitled to compensation of N=30,000.",option:{a:"Contribution",b:"Subrogation",c:"indemnity",d:"Uberrimae fidei"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:289,question:"The division of total loss are",option:{a:"average loss and partial loss",b:"partial loss and full loss",c:"total loss and actual loss",d:"actual total loss and constructive total loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:323,question:"A clause in marine insurance policy prohibiting the insured from giving up a damaged property is",option:{a:"deductible",b:"abandonment",c:"indemnity",d:"compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:339,question:"Which of the following documents forms the basis of a contract in insurance business?",option:{a:"Policy document",b:"Proposal form",c:"Claim form",d:"Discharge form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:345,question:"Which  of  the  following  functions  is  related  to  life assurance contract? Benefits are",option:{a:"determined  on  the  happening  of  insured  event",b:"determined by the indemnity doctrine",c:"determined at the inception of the policy",d:"assessed by the extent of the loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:161,question:"------------- is a policy designed to place the insured in the same financial position as he was immediately before the happening of the event insured against",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Subrogation",c:"Surrender value",d:"Actuary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:59,question:"In insurance contract offeree is the",option:{a:"insured",b:"insurance company",c:"client",d:"Third party"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:258,question:"One of the following is necessary to meet uncertainties in future",option:{a:"profit",b:"capital",c:"borrowing",d:"insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:119,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Insurable risk",c:"Subrogation",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:217,question:"Indemnity is not applicable in",option:{a:"assurance contract",b:"insurance contract",c:"insurance terms",d:"insurance content"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:254,question:"If the insured does not want the contract to continue he receives",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"consideration",c:"premium",d:"commission"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:42,question:"A voucher signed by the insured before collecting his claim is",option:{a:"money collect receipt",b:"discharge voucher",c:"payment receipt",d:"pay - in - slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:331,question:"A motorist travelling from Ghana to Nigeria would be required to obtain one of the following types of motor insurance cover",option:{a:"green card",b:"brown card",c:"yellow card",d:"purple card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:308,question:"A type of re - insurance  where  the re - insurer has  the option  to  accept  or  reject  any  risk  presented  for re-insurance is",option:{a:"stop loss",b:"facultative",c:"treaty",d:"excess of loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:328,question:"The cover that is taken at the option of the motor vehicle owner is",option:{a:"a comprehensive cover",b:"an act only cover",c:"a third party only cover",d:"a special type cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:198,question:"A payment made by insurer as a form of sympathy to maintain goodwill is",option:{a:"Compensation payment",b:"Contract payment",c:"Charity payment",d:"Ex - gratia payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:100,question:"Unlawful breaking and entering into any premises or place of safe keeping is covered under which of these policies?",option:{a:"burglary",b:"business interruption",c:"employers liability",d:"public liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:296,question:"The maximum number of days allowed for a policy holder to pay his renewal premium after it has become due is called",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"conditions",c:"days of grace",d:"days of liberty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:101,question:"When someone is placed back in the same financial position that he was in just prior to a loss, that is ----",option:{a:"Actual cash value",b:"Consideration",c:"Contribution",d:"Indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:30,question:"Which of the following policies is a peril covered under a standard fire policy?",option:{a:"Lightning",b:"Storm",c:"Civil commotion",d:"Escape of oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:325,question:"A fire insurance policy valued at N= 250,000 is issued at the rate of 0.2%. How much would the premium be, if the policy is granted with 5% long - term agreement discount?",option:{a:"N= 475",b:"N= 500",c:"N= 12,500",d:"N= 13,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:55,question:"A  statement  of  fact  that  the insured must have an interest in the object of the contract is called",option:{a:"warranty",b:"insurable interest",c:"subrogation",d:"object interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:205,question:"The coming together of minds of  the two parties to the insurance contract is called",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"acceptance",c:"consensus ad-idem",d:"adhesion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:77,question:"The following are non-insurable except",option:{a:"Lose of profit as a result of change in fashion",b:"Speculation",c:"Lose of profit as a result of maladministration",d:"Fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:64,question:"Which of these is an aid to trade?",option:{a:"cover note",b:"insurance",c:"premium",d:"policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:116,question:"The principle that requires the insured to disclose to the insurer all matters relating to the object of insurance is called",option:{a:"Uberrimae fidei",b:"Proximate cause",c:"Abandonment",d:"Subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:297,question:"The  factor  that has  the  tendency  to  increase  the occurrence of a risk is called",option:{a:"risk",b:"loss",c:"hazard",d:"peril"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:109,question:"In the utmost good faith principle, the value of the subject matter should",option:{a:"Be over stated",b:"Understated",c:"Not be stated",d:"Not be overstated nor understated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:99,question:"A policy designed to protect individuals against negligence while carrying out their daily activities is called",option:{a:"business interruption",b:"employers liability",c:"engineering",d:"professional indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:83,question:"The  principle  of  insurance  which  states  that a person must be in a legally recognized relationship to what is  insured  such  that  he  will  benefit  from its existence or suffer by its loss is",option:{a:"utmost good faith",b:"insurable interest",c:"proximate cause",d:"subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:35,question:"Risk Net Insurance Brokers Limited placed a business with an insurance company, in return the broker will be entitled to",option:{a:"fees",b:"commission",c:"profit",d:"revenue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:21,question:"The document that sets out the list of items covered in insurance is a",option:{a:"manifest",b:"bill of lading",c:"policy list",d:"policy specification or form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:295,question:"Business interruption insurance can also be called",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"constructive loss",c:"partial  loss",d:"general loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:182,question:"A professional officer of an insurance company whose duty among others is to calculate the premium to be 	paid by the insured is called",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Principal",c:"Actuarist",d:"Adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:349,question:"Which of the following factors limits indemnity?",option:{a:"Cession",b:"Re - insurance",c:"Excess",d:"Co - insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:89,question:"Indemnity is provided through the following media except",option:{a:"cash",b:"commission",c:"reinstatement",d:"repair"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:237,question:"A card used by motorist in the West African sub-region is called",option:{a:"insurance certificate",b:"insurance register",c:"insurance green card",d:"Ecowas brown card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:96,question:"“Hull” in marine policy refers to the",option:{a:"boiler",b:"cost of transporting the goods",c:"goods on board",d:"ship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:184,question:"The principle that requires all material facts to be disclosed is known as",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Fidelity",c:"Proximate cause",d:"Utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:80,question:"Hazard that relates to the subject matter of insurance is called",option:{a:"moral",b:"physical",c:"peril",d:"Good peril"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:16,question:"In the preparation of food for eat - in - customers, the cooks made a mistake in using excess quantity of an 	ingredient. A customer ate and  suffered  poisoning. 	Which policy of the operator would pick this liability?",option:{a:"Public liability",b:"Personal liability",c:"All risks insurance",d:"Loss of profit insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:304,question:"In which of the following classes of insurance is no <em>claim discount</em> applicable?",option:{a:"Money insurance",b:"Marine insurance",c:"Motor insurance",d:"Aviation insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:146,question:"Workman compensation is also referred to as",option:{a:"Fidelity insurance",b:"Employment liability",c:"Public liability",d:"Product liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:81,question:"The following are examples of bad moral hazard except",option:{a:"Fraudulent activities",b:"Carelessness",c:"Honesty",d:"Unreasonableness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:23,question:"In property insurance, which of the following is not a direct loss?",option:{a:"Reinstating the property destroyed",b:"Replacing the property destroyed",c:"Repairing the property damaged",d:"Replacing third party property damaged"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:54,question:"The facts which might influence any party’s willingness to enter the contract or reject it is called",option:{a:"insurable fact",b:"insurance fact",c:"insured fact",d:"material fact"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:165,question:"Life assurance provides dual benefits of savings and ------------ to a policy holder",option:{a:"Acceptance",b:"Consideration",c:"Contribution",d:"Security"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:125,question:"A card used by motorist in the West African sub-region is called",option:{a:"Brown card",b:"Certificate",c:"Insurance card",d:"visa card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:46,question:"The alternative to seeking for surrender value in a life assurance contract is",option:{a:"automatic non - forfeiture",b:"revival condition",c:"paid-up policy",d:"standing order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:147,question:"An insurance cover for lawyers, accountants and brokers is",option:{a:"Employment",b:"Professional",c:"Public",d:"Product"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:241,question:"Policy condition which are automatically applicable and not stated in the contract of agreement is known as",option:{a:"agreed condition",b:"agreed negotiation",c:"implied condition",d:"expressed condition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:130,question:"One of the following is the duty of the insured in insurance claim process",option:{a:"Late report of the loss",b:"Little idea of the loss size",c:"Quick report of the loss",d:"Hiding fact"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:124,question:"Cover note usually run for about",option:{a:"One month",b:"Two days",c:"5 years",d:"3 days"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:191,question:"Cover note usually run for about",option:{a:"21 days",b:"one month",c:"12 months",d:"3 month"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:104,question:"The term pooling of risks in insurance means that",option:{a:"Many who face risks pay premium so that those who suffer loss may be reimbursed",b:"Insurance companies share heavy losses",c:"Insurance company re-assures with another",d:"Insurance companies operates pool betting business"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:113,question:"A peril is best defined as",option:{a:"Chance of a loss",b:"The occurrence of a loan",c:"The cause of a loss",d:"The result of a loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:300,question:"One of these is a full time professional",option:{a:"broker",b:"agent",c:"factor",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:257,question:"One of the following is legally used by the insured while the policy is being processed",option:{a:"indemnity form",b:"claim form",c:"cover note",d:"proposal form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:185,question:"In insurance contract, failure to disclose all relevant material facts will render the contract",option:{a:"legal",b:"Voidable",c:"Void",d:"Implied"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:208,question:"An undertaking by the insured that certain things shall be done or not be done or certain things shall be put in place or not in place is called",option:{a:"warranties and representation",b:"utmost good faith and uberrimae fidei",c:"insurable and non-insurable",d:"subrogation and indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:66,question:"Insured is likewise known as",option:{a:"insuree",b:"Insurer",c:"policy holder",d:"contractor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:290,question:"Marine insurance policy which covers all the ship or vessels belonging to one owner is",option:{a:"flect policy",b:"mixed policy",c:"value policy",d:"fixed policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:292,question:"Speailative risks are",option:{a:"insurable risk",b:"non insurable risk",c:"financial risk",d:"non financial risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:201,question:"Insurance is defined as",option:{a:"risking of loss",b:"pooling of risk",c:"gathering of risk",d:"waiving of risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:145,question:"Factor that causes an exposure to injury, loss or damage is",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Hazard",c:"Peril",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:310,question:"One of the features of term assurance is",option:{a:"investment",b:"profit",c:"protection",d:"surrender"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:67,question:"Insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Broker and Agent",b:"Insured and Insurer",c:"Insurer  and Agent",d:"Insured and Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:106,question:"The amount of money paid periodically by an insured to the insurance company to cover risk is called",option:{a:"Commission",b:"Premium",c:"Cover note",d:"Dividend"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:118,question:"The principle of subrogation imposed an obligation on the insured to",option:{a:"Disclose all material information",b:"Have financial risks in the object",c:"Press for compensation",d:"Surrender legal right after compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:47,question:"Which of the following is a risk covered in endowment assurance?",option:{a:"Permanent disability",b:"Bodily injury",c:"Temporary disability",d:"Death cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:32,question:"A contract sold  by  insurance companies that  pay  a monthly or  quarterly income  benefit for the  life  of a person is",option:{a:"endowment",b:"annuity",c:"income",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:122,question:"The policy that covers debt that cannot be recovered is called",option:{a:"Life assurance",b:"Motor vehicle policy",c:"Comprehensive policy",d:"Bad debt insurance policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:244,question:"The process of transferring risk from one insurer to another is called",option:{a:"contribution",b:"re-insurance",c:"re-processing",d:"re-activating"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:269,question:"To which of the following does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"the insurer only",b:"the proposer only",c:"the third party and insured",d:"insurer and proposer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:199,question:"The policy that provides protection for goods or cargoes and ships against the perils of the sea is",option:{a:"Fire",b:"Marine",c:"Aviation",d:"Credit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:142,question:"Amount paid to the beneficiary upon the death of the insured is",option:{a:"Premium",b:"Compensation",c:"Declaration",d:"Death benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:150,question:"The legal right to insure a subject matter is",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Subject Matter",c:"Subrogation",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:102,question:"Insurable interest means",option:{a:"Interest gained on money in a bank",b:"Interest payable on a loan",c:"Financial interest a person has in something he expects to inherit",d:"The financial interest a person has in something of value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:63,question:"The evidence of the contractual agreement between the insured and insurer is",option:{a:"policy",b:"proposal form",c:"insurance certificate",d:"cover note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:206,question:"Uberrimae fidei is equally known as",option:{a:"contract",b:"agreement",c:"consensus",d:"utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:168,question:"A place where the business of insurance is transacted is called a/an",option:{a:"Insurance market",b:"Brokerage firm",c:"Insurance house",d:"Insurance conference room"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:153,question:"The provider of protection to an insurance  company against the excess risk it has given insurance covers is called",option:{a:"Assurer",b:"Insuring",c:"Reinsurer",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:245,question:"A reminder to the insured that this existing contract is due to expire is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"slip",c:"claim form",d:"renewal notice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:341,question:"The right of choice of option for method of indemnity is exercised by the",option:{a:"insured",b:"insurance broker",c:"insurance consultant",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:19,question:"A policy that combines cover for many perils as a single policy  to  suit  the  insurance  needs of  an insured is",option:{a:"accident policy",b:"protection policy",c:"paternal policy",d:"packaged policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:250,question:"The deliberate throwing overboard of part of a cargo without a good intention is called",option:{a:"jettison",b:"barratry",c:"voyaging",d:"overboard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:307,question:"A fire insurance policy guaranteed by the insured to be in place for a stated period with a particular insurer is granted a _____________",option:{a:"no claim discount",b:"fleet discount",c:"long - term agreement discount",d:"plurality discount"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:51,question:"The primary function of insurance is",option:{a:"making profit",b:"managing of risk",c:"spreading of risk",d:"prevention of accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:108,question:"Which of the following is not a function of insurance?",option:{a:"Serves as collateral",b:"Encouraging saving",c:"Provides insecurity",d:"Reduces risks"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:336,question:"The meaning of with <em>profit policy</em>  in life assurance is that the sum assured is paid",option:{a:"without profit",b:"with profit",c:"with interest",d:"without interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:212,question:"An insurance contract which does not involve mutuality of agreement in which only one of the parties involved in the contract makes promises that are legally binding is called",option:{a:"double contract",b:"single contract",c:"multilateral contract",d:"unilateral contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:149,question:"The wrongful act willfully committed by either the master or the prejudice of either the owner or crew to the chatterer of the ship is",option:{a:"Barratry",b:"Caveat emptor",c:"Bailee",d:"Jettison"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:126,question:"Uncertainty of loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Certainty",c:"Insurance",d:"Hazard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:224,question:"Risk that affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"pure risk",c:"fundamental risk",d:"static risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:144,question:"The date on which an insurance or reinsurance contract comes into force is known as",option:{a:"Starting point date",b:"Inception date",c:"Beginning date",d:"Commencement date"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:227,question:"Inter company agreement in which insurers agreed to waive their right against each other for loss is",option:{a:"knock for knock agreement",b:"employers’ liability",c:"tit for tat agreement",d:"salvage agreement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:298,question:"The cause of a loss is",option:{a:"peril",b:"hazard",c:"risk",d:"loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:86,question:"Another name for utmost good faith is",option:{a:"cadent",b:"cede",c:"ex gratia",d:"uberrimae fidei"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:112,question:"Hazard that deals with the human habits and character that arises from human attitude and the conduct of people is called",option:{a:"physical",b:"Moral",c:"Static",d:"Dynamic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:128,question:"The continuation of insurance contract after expiration is",option:{a:"Renewal",b:"Revival",c:"Resuscitation",d:"Rejuvenation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:151,question:"--------- shows what the insured should do or not do to maintain the existence of the policy",option:{a:"Cover note",b:"Policy",c:"Warranty",d:"Certificate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:192,question:"The process of changing anything wrong with the policy to make it current is",option:{a:"Endorsement",b:"Specification",c:"Rectification",d:"Correction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:317,question:"A clause in an insurance policy that makes a claim jointly payable to the policyholder and the third party is",option:{a:"claim clause",b:"mortgagee clause",c:"mortgage clause",d:"joint liability clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:41,question:"A small fixed sum retained by the insured in the form of a claim is",option:{a:"slip",b:"severity",c:"excess",d:"frequency"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:135,question:"The person who calculate the amount given to the insured if he does not want to continue with the contract of insurance is called",option:{a:"Actuary",b:"Insurance agent",c:"Insurance broker",d:"Assessor loss adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"}],n={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:o};export{o as data,n as default,e as message,a as status,i as subject,t as total};
